<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leif Hancox-Li</title>
    <link>http://boltzmann-brain.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Leif Hancox-Li</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 21:48:16 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://boltzmann-brain.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers</title>
      <link>http://boltzmann-brain.github.io/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 21:48:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boltzmann-brain.github.io/papers/</guid>
      <description>A list of published papers and preprints in feminist philosophy and philosophy of physics.
Philosophy of Quantum Field Theory &amp;ldquo;Solutions in Constructive Field Theory,&amp;rdquo; Philosophy of Science 84, no. 2 (April 2017): 335-358.
 On how the concept of a &amp;ldquo;correct solution&amp;rdquo; in mathematically rigorous quantum field theory depends on non-rigorous considerations. Journal link; preprint  &amp;ldquo;Coarse-Graining as a Route to Microscopic Physics: The Renormalization Group in Quantum Field Theory,&amp;rdquo; Philosophy of Science 82, no.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>http://boltzmann-brain.github.io/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 16:42:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boltzmann-brain.github.io/resume/</guid>
      <description>My resume is also available in PDF form. Alternatively, you can view my LinkedIn profile.
Work Technical Writer and Researcher, Capital One 2019 - present
 Write tutorials, conceptual guides, and other documentation for a Kubernetes cloud platform. Do research on fair and explainable machine learning. Write playbook for data scientists providing guidance on best practices for responsible AI.  Senior Technical Writer, Laserfiche 2017 - 2019
 Create, manage, and edit diverse types of documentation, including user guides, configuration guides for systems administrators, and API tutorials for third-party developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://boltzmann-brain.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 21:56:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://boltzmann-brain.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m an NYC-based technical writer who documents a cloud platform for data scientists and software engineers. I also conduct research on fairness and explainability in data science. Prior to this, I was a researcher in fields as diverse as philosophy, computer vision, and physics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>