<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leif Hancox-Li</title>
    <link>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Leif Hancox-Li</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 23:04:09 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This Week in Responsible AI: February 16, 2022</title>
      <link>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/twrai-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 23:04:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/twrai-1/</guid>
      <description>Designing AI
  Speculative friction
  What went wrong with design thinking
  Climate
 AI&amp;rsquo;s carbon footprint  Diversity
 More than 30% of girls in tech don’t become tech undergrads  Legal/policy
 The US patent office issued an RFC on intellectual property made with AI  Explainability
 Facebook releases a &amp;ldquo;Why am I seeing this ad?&amp;rdquo; tool  Fairness
 Common methods to remove ML bias fail to correct for &amp;ldquo;social norm bias&amp;rdquo;  Privacy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Samples</title>
      <link>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 17:05:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/writing/</guid>
      <description>Here are some links to writing samples from my previous roles in software documentation. For my academic writing, see Papers.
I can also provide writing samples that aren&amp;rsquo;t publicly available upon request.
Messagebird writing samples These tutorials for sample Flask/Python apps demo-ing a REST API are from a freelance gig I had a few years ago. I wrote both the sample apps and the tutorials.
 Verify voice guide Notifications guide  Laserfiche writing samples I wrote most of the topics under Customizing a Classic Form with CSS and Javascript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Der Spiegel&#39;s 1987 interview with Joseph Weizenbaum</title>
      <link>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/weizenbaum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/weizenbaum/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, I found this 1987 interview with the early AI researcher-turned-AI skeptic Joseph Weizenbaum. It covers a lot of ground, such as the military-industrial complex, whether computers can capture human experience, and other points that today&amp;rsquo;s AI skeptics will be sympathetic to. (These themes were also covered in longer form in his book, Computer Power and Human Reason.) As far as I know, there isn&amp;rsquo;t an English translation of this interview available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My journey from academia into technical writing</title>
      <link>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/academia-tech-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 18:47:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/academia-tech-writing/</guid>
      <description>Occasionally, unhappy academics ask me for advice on how to get non-academic jobs. Few of them consider technical writing as a career option, and I think more of them should&amp;mdash;technical writing values skills that many academics already have, and provides similar intellectual challenges, but with greater career flexibility than academia has.
Here, I&amp;rsquo;ll describe my journey into technical writing and why I found it fulfilling, adding on some basic advice and views on the technical writing job market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternative computing styles and gender</title>
      <link>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/pluralism-cs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 19:40:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/pluralism-cs/</guid>
      <description>Lizzie Kumar and I recently co-authored a paper at FAccT that applied feminist epistemology to explanation methods in machine learning. People must have liked it, because we won a best paper award for it. One of the points we made, borrowing from feminist epistemology, is that we could do with more epistemological pluralism when it comes to evaluating these methods, and that we should consider if certain dominant computing values cause us to over-trust some explanation methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epistemic dynamics and gender in the philosophy of physics</title>
      <link>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/dotson-phil-physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 16:23:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/dotson-phil-physics/</guid>
      <description>There was no shortage of women who entered my PhD program wanting to do philosophy of physics. There were as many of them, in my time there, as there were men interested in the same. Yet in the end, much fewer women ended up specializing in that, by the time they left the program.
Why? Here&amp;rsquo;s what would happen:
  A woman would be admitted with a philosophy of physics interest and enthusiastically start taking the philosophy of physics courses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Don&#39;t Defend Professional Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 15:38:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/ethics/</guid>
      <description>As a former professional philosopher who now does research on responsible AI, I&amp;rsquo;ve been to multiple events where someone working on the social impacts of AI will make a negative remark about philosophy. Typically, their criticism implicitly targets the dominant strain of academic philosophy in the Anglophone tradition, encompassing the various analytic approaches to ethics. As an ex-philosopher who finds my background in philosophy of science sometimes useful to my AI research, I might be expected to defend my former field, but in fact I largely agree with the criticisms and think on the whole that it would not be helpful to respond to these criticisms by listing the various &amp;ldquo;exceptions&amp;rdquo; to the rule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Literary Social Science in Milkman and Uncanny Valley</title>
      <link>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/milkman-uncanny-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/milkman-uncanny-valley/</guid>
      <description>I recently happened to read two books in close succession that, unbeknownst to me before my readings, were both what I&amp;rsquo;m calling literary social science&amp;mdash;which is particularly striking given that one book is fiction and the other is a memoir. Anna Burns&#39; Milkman is a fictional narrative by a teenager in Northern Ireland during the Troubles, and Anna Wiener&amp;rsquo;s Uncanny Valley is a memoir of Wiener&amp;rsquo;s stint working in Silicon Valley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers</title>
      <link>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 21:48:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/papers/</guid>
      <description>A list of my published papers and preprints in philosophy of machine learning, feminist philosophy, and philosophy of physics. You can also view a copy of my academic CV here.
Philosophy of Machine Learning &amp;ldquo;Should attention be all we need? The epistemic and ethical implications of unification in machine learning.&amp;rdquo; Forthcoming in Conference on Fairness, Accountability, and Transparency (FAccT ’22). Co-authored with Nic Fishman.
 Assesses the epistemic and ethical risks/benefits of the trend towards unified model architectures in machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 16:42:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/resume/</guid>
      <description>My resume is also available in PDF form. Alternatively, you can view my LinkedIn profile.
Work Senior Data Scientist, Capital One 2020 - present
 Do research on fair and explainable machine learning, including internal user studies and peer-reviewed work on methodological issues. Research and implement technical explainability solutions (SHAP, LIME, GAMs) for black-box machine learning models, customizing dashboards and visualizations to user needs. Educate other Capital One data scientists on best practices for responsible AI through both written materials and talks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 21:56:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a data scientist who does interdisciplinary research on responsible AI and helps data science teams make their models more explainable. I excel at bringing a humanistic perspective to technical issues while also having the skills to implement technical solutions that take social values into account. My research has won best paper awards at both FAccT and the Philosophy of Science Association.
Prior to this, I was a technical writer for a variety of software products, ranging from MLOps to REST APIs to complicated enterprise GUIs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
