<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Leif Hancox-Li</title>
    <link>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Leif Hancox-Li</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 18:47:10 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/academia-tech-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 18:47:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/academia-tech-writing/</guid>
      <description>Occasionally, unhappy academics ask me for advice on how to get non-academic jobs. Few of them consider technical writing as a career option, and I think more of them should&amp;mdash;technical writing values skills that many academics already have, and provides similar intellectual challenges, but with greater career flexibility than academia has.
Here, I&amp;rsquo;ll describe my journey into technical writing and why I found it fulfilling, adding on some basic advice and views on the technical writing job market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternative computing styles and gender</title>
      <link>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/pluralism-cs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 19:40:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/pluralism-cs/</guid>
      <description>Lizzie Kumar and I recently co-authored a paper at FAccT that applied feminist epistemology to explanation methods in machine learning. People must have liked it, because we won a best paper award for it. One of the points we made, borrowing from feminist epistemology, is that we could do with more epistemological pluralism when it comes to evaluating these methods, and that we should consider if certain dominant computing values cause us to over-trust some explanation methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epistemic dynamics and gender in the philosophy of physics</title>
      <link>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/dotson-phil-physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 16:23:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/dotson-phil-physics/</guid>
      <description>There was no shortage of women who entered my PhD program wanting to do philosophy of physics. There were as many of them, in my time there, as there were men interested in the same. Yet in the end, much fewer women ended up specializing in that, by the time they left the program.
Why? Here&amp;rsquo;s what would happen:
 A woman would be admitted with a philosophy of physics interest and enthusiastically start taking the philosophy of physics courses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Don&#39;t Defend Professional Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 15:38:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/ethics/</guid>
      <description>As a former professional philosopher who now does research on responsible AI, I&amp;rsquo;ve been to multiple events where someone working on the social impacts of AI will make a negative remark about philosophy. Typically, their criticism implicitly targets the dominant strain of academic philosophy in the Anglophone tradition, encompassing the various analytic approaches to ethics. As an ex-philosopher who finds my background in philosophy of science sometimes useful to my AI research, I might be expected to defend my former field, but in fact I largely agree with the criticisms and think on the whole that it would not be helpful to respond to these criticisms by listing the various &amp;ldquo;exceptions&amp;rdquo; to the rule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Literary Social Science in Milkman and Uncanny Valley</title>
      <link>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/milkman-uncanny-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://boltzmann-brain.github.io/posts/milkman-uncanny-valley/</guid>
      <description>I recently happened to read two books in close succession that, unbeknownst to me before my readings, were both what I&amp;rsquo;m calling literary social science&amp;mdash;which is particularly striking given that one book is fiction and the other is a memoir. Anna Burns&amp;rsquo; Milkman is a fictional narrative by a teenager in Northern Ireland during the Troubles, and Anna Wiener&amp;rsquo;s Uncanny Valley is a memoir of Wiener&amp;rsquo;s stint working in Silicon Valley.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>